Guide to the Alfred B. Fitt, Special Assistant to the President of Yale University for Community and Alumni Affairs, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Alfred B. Fitt, special assistant to the president of Yale University for community and alumni affairs, records
1969-1975
RU 446
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
(8 boxes)
The records consist of the administrative files of Alfred B. Fitt documenting his role as special assistant for community and alumni affairs.
Yale University. President's Office
Fitt, Alfred B.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-B (YRG 2-B), Records of Yale presidential assistants.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of the administrative files of Alfred B. Fitt documenting his role as special assistant for community and alumni affairs.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Public relations; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale University. President's Office
- Records of Alfred B. Fitt as special assistant to the president concerning community and alumni affairs, 1969-1975; Accession 1978-A-013
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research. Restricted folders are identified with their restriction review date.
  - A Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Admissions (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action plans and correspondence (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Studies Program (Box 1)
  - Alien employment certification (Box 1)
  - Yale Alumni - members of Congress (Box 1)
  - Yale Alumni - Commission on Alumni Affairs (Box 1)
  - Yale Alumni Members of Congress (Mailing) (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education, Committee on Taxation (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 1)
  - Anderson correspondence (Box 1)
  - Association of Governing Boards (Box 1)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU), Council on Federal (Box 1)
  - Relations (Box 1)
  - AAU, University Discrimination against Women in Employment (Box 1)
  - AAU, ROTC (Box 1)
  - AAU (Box 1)
  - AAU, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Athletic Association (Box 1)
  - B Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Brewster, K.B., Jr. - speeches (Box 1)
  - Brewster, K.B., Jr. - letters (copies) written by ABF (Box 1)
  - Brewster, K.B., Jr. - letters (copies)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
  - Brewster, K.B., Jr. - memos
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
    - 1969 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and grounds planning (Box 1)
  - C Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Campus disorders
    - 1971 (Box 2)
    - 1970 (Box 2)
    - 1969 (Box 2)
  - Church Council of Church of Christ in Yale (Box 2)
  - Combined Charities Board (Box 2)
  - Commission for Higher Education, State of Connecticut (Box 2)
  - Yale Council on Community Affairs (Box 2)
  - Community Affairs
    - 1971 (Box 2)
    - 1970 (Box 2)
  - Community Affairs, special projects (Box 2)
  - Community Progress, Inc (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Conference of Independent Colleges
    - 1975 (Box 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1972 (Box 2)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Mental Health Center (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Mental Health Center review meetings (Box 2)
  - Contingency repayment loans (Box 2)
  - Cort Speech (Bethlehem Steel Corp.) (Box 2)
  - Consortium on financing higher education (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, Alfred B. Fitt, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, outgoing
    - 1974 (Box 2)
    - 1972 (Box 2)
  - D Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Davenport College (Box 2)
  - Department of Defense (Box 2)
  - Development Board (Box 2)
  - Discrimination
    - Admissions to medical and nursing schools (Box 2)
    - Aliens, employment (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
    - Sex - ABF memorandum of 1970 Sep 18 and related correspondence (Box 2)
    - Housing (Box 2)
    - Race (Box 2)
    - Age, campus police (Box 2)
    - Sex, admissions (Box 2)
    - Women, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Women at Yale, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Sex, employment (Box 3)
    - Sex, admissions - 1971 legislation (Box 3)
    - Undergraduate scholarships for women (Box 3)
  - E Correspondence (Box 3)
  - F Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Federal Student Unrest Amendment (Box 3)
  - Federal Support Programs, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
  - Foreign language and area study appropriations and foreign students (Box 3)
  - Foreign aid (Overseas Development Council) (Box 3)
  - Forestry School (Box 3)
  - G Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Glee Club (Box 3)
  - Government - university relations (Box 3)
  - Guaranteed Educational Loan Program (G.E.L.P.) (Box 3)
  - H Correspondence (Box 3)
  - HEW compliance (Box 3)
  - Health, Education and Welf.are (HEW) (Box 3)
  - Higher Education General Assistance Act of 1970 (H.R. 16622) (Box 3)
  - Higher Education and Nixon Administration (Box 3)
  - Hill Neighborhood Corporation (HNC) (Box 3)
  - Hospital - Yale-New Haven (Box 3)
  - Hospital - Yale-New Haven
    - Annual report (Box 3)
    - Budget and finance (Box 3)
    - Financial statements (Box 3)
    - Meeting of Development and Public Relation Committee (Box 3)
    - Joint Conference Committee (Box 3)
    - Joint board meetings (Box 3)
    - Medical Committee of the Board (Box 3)
    - Meetings of committee on the role of the hospital in the community (Box 3)
    - Proposal changes - medical staff by-laws, rules and regulations (Box 3)
    - Staff selection policy (Box 3)
    - Personnel Committee meetings (Box 3)
  - House Internal Security Committee (Box 3)
  - Housing Committee (Box 3)
  - Housing (Yale) (Box 3)
  - Mailing on H.R. 7248 (Box 3)
  - I Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Institutional Policies Committee (Box 4)
  - International Association of Universities (Box 4)
  - Ivy Group Committee on Administration (Box 4)
  - Investment Policy (Box 4)
  - Ivy League Athletics (Box 4)
  - J Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Justice Department (U.S.) (Box 4)
  - K Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Kolakowski, 1974 (Box 4)
    Restricted until January 1, 2051.
  - L Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Law Enforcement Education Program (LEEP) (Box 4)
  - Law School seminar (Box 4)
  - Legal Services (Box 4)
  - Library privileges (Box 4)
  - Liquor control (Wiggin and Dana) (Box 4)
  - Low income housing (Box 4)
  - M Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Manpower Act (Box 4)
  - May Day, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Mellon Center (Box 4)
  - Military Procurement Bill (Box 4)
  - Mory's (Box 4)
  - Moratorium Committee (Box 4)
  - Moot Court (Box 4)
  - N Correspondence (Box 4)
  - National Coalition for a Responsible Congress (Box 4)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) (Box 4)
  - NCAA - Eastern College Athletic Conference (Box 4)
  - National Corporation for Housing Partnerships (Box 4)
  - National Defense Education Act (NDEA) (Box 4)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 4)
  - National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) (Box 4)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) (Box 4)
  - Navy phase-out plans (Box 4)
  - Negro servicemen separations (registry) (Box 4)
  - New Haven - Yale relationships (Box 4)
  - News Bureau (Box 4)
  - O Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Organized Crime Control Act of 1970 (Box 4)
  - P Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Personnel (Box 4)
  - Placement Office (Box 4)
  - Police (Yale Police Board) (Box 4)
    Restricted unti January 1, 2050.
  - Police (Yale Police correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Police - Yale (confidential) (Box 4)
    Restricted until January 1, 2050.
  - Police - Yale and the Police (Box 4)
  - Policy - athletic facilities (Box 4)
  - Policy - University halls meeting facilities (Box 4)
  - Political Science Department (Box 4)
  - Press release - Nixon speeches,New York Times (Box 4)
  - R Correspondence (Box 4)
  - ROTC
    - 1973-1975 (Box 4)
    - 1972 (Box 4)
    - 1971 (Box 4)
    - 1970 Jan - Jun (Box 4)
    - 1970 Jul - Dec (Box 5)
    - 1969 (Box 5)
  - Representatives, House of, Yale Alumni Members (Box 5)
  - S Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Safeguard anti-ballistic missile (Box 5)
  - Scranton report (Box 5)
  - Selective Service (Box 5)
  - Selective Service reform (Box 5)
  - Senate Finance Committee (Box 5)
  - Sponsored Research - Princeton (Box 5)
  - Stanford University (Box 5)
  - State Support Programs (Box 5)
  - 1971 Strike by Local 35 (Box 5)
  - Strike - Local 35, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Student Assistance Act of 1969 (Box 5)
  - Student Community Housing Corporation (Box 5)
  - Student complaints - housekeeping and maintenance (Box 5)
  - Students - legal (Box 5)
  - Student voting (Box 5)
  - Summer film program (Box 5)
  - Summer placement (Box 5)
  - T Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Memoranda for Charles H. Taylor, Jr. (Box 5)
  - Tax - Michigan (Box 5)
  - Tax - New Haven
    - 1971 Jan (Box 5)
    - 1970 Sep - Dec (Box 5)
    - 1970 Jan - Jul (Box 5)
  - Tax problems - fellowships (Box 5)
  - Taxes - West Haven (Box 5)
  - Tax reform - charitable gifts
    - 1971 Jan (Box 5)
    - 1970 Jul-Dec (Box 5)
    - 1970 Jan-Jun (Box 5)
    - 1969 (Box 5)
  - Legislation (gift tax) proposed (Box 5)
  - TIAA - CREF legislation (S. 1290) (Box 5)
  - Tuition Postponement Plan (Box 5)
  - U Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Unemployment compensation (Box 5)
  - United Nations (Box 5)
  - United Way (Box 5)
  - University Committee on Classified Information (Box 5)
  - University Foundation relations (Box 5)
  - University calendar (Box 5)
  - Urban Fellows Program (Box 5)
  - Urban Studies (Box 5)
  - U.S. Grant Program (Box 5)
  - V Correspondence (Box 5)
  - W Correspondence (Box 5)
  - War - Vietnam, statement (Box 6)
  - War - Vietnam (Box 6)
  - War - Vietnam veterans (Box 6)
  - Correspondence from Wiggin and Dana (Box 6)
  - Y Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Yale budget and policy procedures, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Yale Industry Committee/Seminars (Box 6)
  - Yale legislative services (Box 6)
  - Yale-New Haven ETV (Box 6)
  - Yale Political Union (Box 6)
  - Yale real estate (Box 6)
  - Yale School of Medicine (Box 6)
  - Yale student aid (Box 6)
  - Position paper (Box 6)
  - ACE and AAU Letter (Box 6)
  - Tax reform
    - Congressional Record (Box 6)
    - Listening Post committee minutes (Box 6)
    - 1969 Dec 5 (Box 6)
    - 1969 Dec 1 - 4 (Box 6)
    - 1969 Nov 1 - 30 (Box 6)
    - 1969 Oct 16 - 31 (Box 6)
    - 1969 Oct 1 - 15 (Box 6)
    - 1969 Sep 15 - 30 (Box 6)
  - Tax reform H.R. 13270
    - 1969 Sep 1 - 14 (Box 6)
    - 1969 Aug 1 - 31 (Box 7)
    - 1969 Mar 18 - Aug 1 (Box 7)
  - Tax reform - Kingman Brewster's special mailing, 1969 August 28 (Box 7)
  - Tax reform - survey of Connecticut colleges re: gifts of securities (Box 7)
  - Tax reform - position paper: gifts of appreciated property, House Bill (Box 7)
  - Report: "International Programs of U. S. Colleges and Universities", 1971 (Box 7)
  - Yale University Affirmative Action plan, 1973 April 25 (Box 7)
  - Tuition postponement option (TPO) (Box 7)
  - TPO (Box 7)
  - Housing at Yale (Box 7)
  - Housing plan (Box 7)
  - Memorandum to Kingman Brews ter on federal contract compliance (Box 7)
  - Sent to Archives, 1972 March (Box 7)
  - Yale Alumni - board meetings (Box 8)
  - National Alumni Meeting (Box 8)
  - American Association of Junior Colleges (Box 8)
  - American Bar Association (Box 8)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 8)
  - Army, Gates Report: All Volunteer Armed Force (Box 8)
  - Association of American Colleges (Box 8)
  - Association of American Universities: Health Professions Education legislation (Box 8)
  - Barron's Educational Series, Inc. (Box 8)
  - Black Coalition (Box 8)
  - Black Students at Yale (BSAY) (Box 8)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 8)
  - Dag Hammarskjold College (Box 8)
  - American Council on Education: Report of Special Committee on Campus Tensions (Box 8)
  - Black Panthers (Box 8)
  - Bryn Mawr - Wofford Inaugural Address (Box 8)
  - Brock Report (Box 8)
  - Calvin Hill Day Care Center (Box 8)
  - Calvin Hill Day Care Center meetings (Box 8)
  - Camp, summer - legislation (Box 8)
  - Child Study Center (Box 8)
  - Department of Defense Referral Program (Box 8)
  - Dwight Chapel organ (Box 8)
  - Eastern College Athletic Conference (ECAC) (Box 8)
  - ECAC - replies to Brewster's Feb 6 and Mar 16 letters (Box 8)
  - ECAC - meetings (Box 8)
  - Education Improvement Center New Haven, Inc. (Box 8)
  - Elections (1970) Senate and House fact sheet (Box 8)
  - Politics, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Politics - Program at Western Michigan (Box 8)
  - Pollution control (Yale) (Box 8)
  - Project One Hundred Thousand (Box 8)
  - Residential college fellowships (Box 8)
  - Senate permanent subcommittee - investigations (Box 8)
  - Senate Finance Committee - mailing (Box 8)
  - W Correspondence (Box 8)
  - War, Cambodia: The Bingharn Record (Box 8)
  - War, Cambodia: Cooper-Church Amendment (Box 8)
  - War, Vietnam: Lawyers Military Defense Committee (Box 8)
  - War, Vietnam: Lawyers on Vietnam Policy (Box 8)
  - War, Vietnam: plans for peace (Box 8)
  - New Haven Foundation:
    - Distribution committee meetings and memo (Box 8)
    - Log-in application (Box 8)
    - New Haven Public Schools (Box 8)
    - Teen Leadership Training Institute (Box 8)
    - Major findings and recommendations (Box 8)
    - Distribution committee meetings and correspondence, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Catalogues (Box 8)
  - New Haven Foundation (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia Higher Education Assistance Agency (PHEAA)
    - Agreements (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Re: Amicus Brief (Box 8)
    - Mailings (Box 8)
    - Legal Briefs (Box 8)